Neil V. Rosenberg bluegrass music collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Sound recordings, Digital files are located in afc2002009_dc001. Please see the AFC reference staff for access.
  - Bluegrass Anthology 22, AFC 2002/009: Bluegrass Anthology 22; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Grand Ole Opry, May 18, 1963
        - "Muleskinner Blues" - Osborne Brothers
        - "Ida Red" - Stringbean [David Akeman]
        - "Ruby" - Osborne Brothers
      - Stoneman Family with Scott Stoneman, May 19, 1963
        Recorded at the afternoon show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana.
        - "Old Joe Clark"
        - "Slewfoot"
        - "White House Blues" ("Unlucky Road to Washington") - Pop Stoneman
        - "Foggy Mountain Breakdown"
        - "Mama Don't Allow"
        - "Poor Ellen Smith"
    - Side 2
      - Stoneman Family
        Continued from Side 1. Continued on SR052.
        - "Let Me Fall, Little Girl, Let Me Fall"
        - "White Lightnin' Number Two"
        - "Wildwood Flower"
        - "Orange Blossom Special"
        - "Pike County Breakdown"
        - "John Henry"
        - "Scotland"
        - "Time After Time"
  - Bluegrass Anthology 23, AFC 2002/009: Bluegrass Anthology 23; RXI 0215; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:12, Side 2: 00:32:11): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Jack Cooke (guitar), Jack Noel (bass), Joe Stuart (lead guitar), Roger Smith (banjo); Tex Watson, Ed Taggart (banjo), Marvin Hedrick, tenor guitar), September 20, 1959
        Backstage jam session, recorded at the Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana.
        - "We'll Meet Again, Sweetheart"
          Hedrick - lead
        - "I'm Coming Back But I Don't Know When"
          Cook - lead
        - "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms"
        - "I'll Still Write Your Name in the Sand"
        - "East Virginia"
        - "All the Good Times"
        - "Weeping Willow"
          Smith - lead, Cook - tenor
        - "Only By You"
        - "I Wonder Where You Are Tonight"
        - "Sweetheart You Done Me Wrong"
        - "That's When I'll Stop Loving You"
        - "Molly and Tenbrooks"
          Cook (lead?)
        - "Pig in a Pen"
        - "Shucking the Corn"
      - Dubs of 45 rpm records
        - "You Broke Your Promise" - Lonesome Pine Fiddlers
        - "Country Preacher" - Masters Family
        - "Gone Home" - Carl Story
          Mercury [?]; Red Rector, mandolin
    - Side 2
      - Dubs of singles
        - "So Blue" - Stanley Brothers, 1955
          Mercury 70612 (YW 7716)
        - "I Long to See the Old Folks" - The Stanley Brothers and the Clinch Mountain Boys, 1954
          Mercury 70340 (YW 7522)
        - "You Can Feel It In Your Soul" - Flatt and Scruggs, 1955
        - "You're Drifting Away" - Bill Monroe, 1953
          Decca 28608 (81273)
      - Bill Monroe: Charlie Cline (G), Gordon Terry (fiddle), Bobby Hicks (b), 1954
        Recorded at the Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Continued on Bluegrass Anthology 24.
        - "Fire on the Mountain"
        - "Letter From My Darlin'"
        - "Lonesome Road Blues"
        - "White House Blues"
        - "Close By"
        - "Bluegrass Stomp"
        - "Wrong Side of the Track"
          Jack Perry
        - "I Cried Again"
        - "Old Home Town"
        - "Cry, Cry Darlin'"
          Terry, Hicks, Cline
  - Bluegrass Anthology 24, AFC 2002/009: Bluegrass Anthology 24; RXI 0214; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:04, Side 2: 00:31:08): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Bill Monroe: Charlie Cline (G), Gordon Terry (fiddle), Bobby Hicks (b), 1954
        Continued from Bluegrass Anthology 23.
        - "Cry, Cry Darlin'"
          Hicks, Terry, Cline
        - "One By One"
        - "Angels Rock Me to Sleep"
          Jack Perry, Cline, Terry, Monroe
        - "I Want the Lord to Protect My Soul"
        - "Grey Eagle"
        - "Johnson's Old Grey Mule"
      - Dubs of records
        - "Walking in Jerusalem Just Like John" - Bill Monroe, 1953
          Decca 28608
        - "Close By" - Bill Monroe, 1954
          Decca 29289
        - "Tree of Life" - Reno and Smiley, 1954
          King 1352
        - "I Could Cry" - Reno and Smiley, 1953
          King 1283 (3539)
        - "You're Not A Drop In The Bucket" - Flatt and Scruggs, 1954
        - "The Lord's Last Supper" - Reno and Smiley, 1952
          King 1128
        - "Someone Will Love Me in Heaven" - Reno and Smiley, 1954
    - Side 2
      - Radio dubs recorded by Marvin Hedrick, circa 1954-1959
        Continued on Bluegrass Anthology 25.
        - "Tragic Romance" - Toby Stroud (and Judy Snyder)
        - "Poison Love" - Toby Stroud
        - "After Dark" - Toby Stroud
        - "Orange Blossom Special" - Toby Stroud
        - "Are You Teasin' Me" - Toby Stroud
        - "John Henry" - Toby Stroud
        - "Not a Drop in the Bucket" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Will You Be Loving Another Man" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Head Over Heels in Love With You" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Have You Come to Say Goodbye" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Foggy Mountain Breakdown" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Hand in Hand" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "I Still Write Your Name in the Sand" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Two More Years" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Cumberland Gap" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Davy Crockett" - Mac Wiseman
  - Bluegrass Anthology 25, AFC 2002/009: Bluegrass Anthology 25; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:32:14, Side 2: 00:32:10): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Continued from Bluegrass Anthology 24; continued on Bluegrass Anthology 26.
    - Side 1
      - Radio dubs recorded by Marvin Hedrick, circa 1954-1959
        - "Close By" - Bill Monroe
        - [steel guitar] - Mac Wiseman
        - "I Haven't Got the Right" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Georgia Rose" - Buzz Busby
        - "Wait a Little Longer Please Jesus" - Bill Monroe
        - "Boat of Love" - Bill Monroe
          Decca 46254 (76142)
        - "When I Get the Money Made" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Steel Guitar Chimes" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Me and My Fiddle" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Waiting for the Boys" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Let Me Borrow Your Heart" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Spanish Fandango" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Black Mountain Rag" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Salty Dog Blues" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "I'll Never Shed Another Tear" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "I Didn't Know" - Mac Wiseman
    - Side 2
      - Radio dubs recorded by Marvin Hedrick, circa 1954-1959
        - "Don't Tell Me Your Troubles" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Molly and Tenbrooks" - Mac Wiseman
        - "A Voice From On High" - Bill Monroe
        - "Will the Roses Bloom in Heaven" - Mac Wiseman
        - "White House Blues" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Let Me Love You One More Time" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Georgia Rose" - Bill Monroe
        - "Whoa Mule" - Toby Stroud
        - "Why Not Confess" - Toby Stroud
        - "Put My Rubber Dolly Away" - Mac Wiseman
        - [fiddle] - Mac Wiseman
        - "Driftwood on the Tide" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Pike County Breakdown" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Turkey in the Straw" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Country Church" - Toby Stroud
        - "Flint Hill Special" - Toby Stroud
        - "Ashes of Love" - Toby Stroud
  - Bluegrass Anthology 26, AFC 2002/009: Bluegrass Anthology 26; RXI 0177; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:32:01, Side 2: 00:31:50): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      Continued from Bluegrass Anthology 25.
      - Radio dubs recorded by Marvin Hedrick, circa 1954-1959
        - "Will You Be Lovin' Another Man" - Toby Stroud
        - "True Life Blues" - Bill Monroe
        - "Love and Wealth" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Come Back to Me" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Sally Goodin" - Mac Wiseman
        - "'Til the End of the World Rolls Around" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "A Hundred Years From Now" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Blue Ridge Mountain Home" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Angels Rock Me to Sleep" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Ain't Nobody Gonna Miss Me When I'm Gone" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Your Love Is Like A Flower" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Leather Britches" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Nobody Loves Me, Nobody Cares" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Tomorrow May Never Come" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Foggy Mountain Special" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Homestead on the Farm" - Mac Wiseman
    - Side 2
      - Radio dubs recorded by Marvin Hedrick, circa 1954-1959
        - "Old Joe Clark" - Mac Wiseman
        - "Flint Hill Special" - Mac Wiseman
      - Dubs of commercial recordings
        - "Ten Paces" - Reno and Smiley, 1962
          King 5673 (11226)
        - "When the Golden Leaves Begin to Fall" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1950
          Decca 46283 (80072)
        - "Lord Protect My Soul" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1951
          Decca 46305 (80073)
        - "River of Death" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1951
          Decca 46305 (80074)
        - "Get Down on Your Knees and Pray" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1951
          Decca 46351/ED2354
        - "I'm On My Way to the Old Home" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1952
          Decca 28045 (75813)
        - "Memories of Mother and Dad" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1952
          Decca 28878 (83133)
        - "He Will Set Your Fields on Fire" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1954
          Decca 29196/ED2354
        - "I'm Working on a Building" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1954
          Decca 29346/ED2354
        - "Come Go With Me" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1960
          Decca 31031 (108, 460)
  - Bluegrass Anthology 27, AFC 2002/009: Bluegrass Anthology 27; RXI 0213; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:32:06, Side 2: 00:32:04): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Dubs of commercial recordings
        - "Memories of You" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1950
          Decca 46266 (75812)
        - "Highway of Sorrow" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1951
          Decca 46369 (80926)
        - "Travelin' Blues" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1951
          Decca 46380 (80792)
        - "Letter From My Darlin'" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1952
          Decca 46392 (80434)
        - "Dark As the Night, Blue As the Day" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1959
          Decca 30944 (106, 541)
        - "Lonesome Wind Blues" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1960
          Decca 31031 (108, 458)
      - Reno and Smiley; John Palmer (bass), Mack Magaha (fiddle), 1958
        Recorded at the Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Part 3, continued from SR049 and SR051.
        - "Someone Will Love Me in Heaven"
        - "Echoes from the Burning Bush"
        - "Springtime in Heaven"
        - "John Henry"
          Twin banjos with Roger Smith
        - "Weeping Willow"
        - "Kicking Mule"
        - "Chicken Hot Rod"
          Comedy routine. Continued on Side 2.
    - Side 2
      - Reno and Smiley; John Palmer (bass), Mack Magaha (fiddle), 1958
        - "Chicken Hot Rod"
          Comedy routine. Continued from Side 1.
      - Dubs from commercial recordings
        - "The Forgotten Soldier Boy" - Monroe Brothers, 1937
          BB 6829
        - "All the Good Times Are Passed and Gone" - Monroe Brothers, 1937
          BB 7191
        - "Let Us Be Lovers Again" - Monroe Brothers, 1937
        - "I'm On My Way Back Home" - Monroe Brothers, 1938
          BB 7460
        - "Pearly Gates" - Monroe Brothers, 1938
        - "Little Joe" - Monroe Brothers, 1938
          BB 7598
        - "On the Banks of the Ohio" - Monroe Brothers, 1938
          BB 7385
        - "You've Got to Walk That Lonesome Valley" - Monroe Brothers, 1936
        - "God Holds the Future in His Hands" - Monroe Brothers, 1936
        - "Were You There?" - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1942
          Bluebird 8953
  - Bluegrass Anthology 28, AFC 2002/009: Bluegrass Anthology 28; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Side 1: 00:45:45, Side 2: 00:46:20): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Dubs of commercial recordings by Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys
        - "Sweetheart, You Done Me Wrong," 1948
          Columbia 20423 (CCO 3880)
        - "That Home Above," 1948
          Columbia 20488 (CCO 4882)
        - "When You Are Lonely," 1949
          Columbia 20526 (CCO 4886)
        - "Will You Be Lovin' Another Man?," 1946
          Columbia 20189 (CCO 4613)
        - "My Little Cabin Home On The Hill," 1947
          Columbia 20459 (CCO 4877)
        - "How Will I Explain About You?," 1946
          Columbia 20384 (CCO 4614)
        - "Blue Yodel #4," 1947
          Columbia 37565 (CCO 4612)
        - "I Hear A Sweet Voice Calling," 1947
          Columbia 20459 (CCO 4876)
        - "I'm Traveling On and On," 1947
          Columbia 20402 (CCO 4889)
        - "It's Mighty Dark to Travel," 1949
          Columbia 20526 (CCO 4875)
        - "Little Community Church," 1948
          Columbia 20488 (CCO 4884)
        - "Shine, Hallelujah, Shine," 1948
          Columbia 20402 (CCO 4888)
        - "Alabama Waltz," 1950
          Decca 46236 (75814)
        - "I'm Blue, I'm Lonesome," 1950
          Decca 46254 (75815)
        - "Boat of Love," 1950
        - "Poison Love," 1951
          Decca 46298 (80437)
    - Side 2
      - Dubs of commercial recordings by Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys
        - "On the Old Kentucky Shore," 1951
          Decca 46298 (80435)
        - "Kentucky Waltz," 1951
          Decca 46314 (80725)
        - "Swing Low, Sweet Chariot," 1951
          Decca 46325 (80727)
        - "Angels Rock Me to Sleep," 1951
          Decca 46325 (80728)
        - "Rotation Blues," 1951
          Decca 46344 (81249)
        - "When the Cactus Is In Bloom," 1952
          Decca 28183 (80793)
        - "Sailor's Plea," 1952
          Decca 28183 (80921)
        - "A Mighty Pretty Waltz," 1952
          Decca 28356 (83171)
        - "Cabin of Love," 1953
          Decca 28749 (81274)
        - "Country Waltz," 1953
          Decca 28749 (83135)
        - "Changing Partners," 1954
          Decca 28021 (85697)
      - Dubs of commercial recordings by Hal Poindexter and the Country Boys
        - "I Ain't Gonna Worry," 1962
          Hi-Lee 45C-1804 (MB-2625)
        - "Carolina Sweetheart," 1962
          Hi-Lee 45C-1804 (MB-2624)
      - Dubs of commercial recordings by Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys
        - "Plant Some Flowers By My Grave," 1962
          Decca DL 4327
        - "Thinking About You," 1962
          Decca DL 4303 (Grand Ole Opry, Saturday night)
        - "I'll Meet You in the Church Sunday Morning," 1951
          Decca 46351 (76141)
  - Bluegrass Anthology 29, AFC 2002/009: Bluegrass Anthology 29; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, Side 1: 00:27:27, Side 2: 00:29:32): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Dubs from commercial recordings
        - "Dixie Look Away" - Country Gentlemen, 1958
          Starday 45-408A
        - "Deep South" - Bill Emerson - John Hall, 1958
        - "Swamp Fever" - Dobber Johnson, 1958
        - "It's a Sin" - Reno and Smiley, 1962
          King 5728 (K11313)
        - "Grandfather's Clock" - Reno and Smiley, 1962
          King 5728 (K11320)
      - Grand Ole Opry show, probably October 19, 1964
        - Corn flakes
          8:30-9 p.m. time slot. Possibly an advertisement.
        - "Truck Driver Queen" - Bill Napier and Charlie Moore
          8:30-9 p.m. time slot
        - Corn flakes
        - Martha White theme - Jim and Jesse
          9 p.m. time slot
        - "Wabash Cannon Ball" - Roy Acuff
        - "I Saw the Light" - Roy Acuff
        - Martha White - T. Tommy, Jim and Jesse
        - "Nine Pound Hammer" - Jim and Jesse
          9 p.m. time slot. F5 is out of tune.
        - Martha White [sic] - Jim and Jesse
          9 p.m. time slot. Probably the Martha White theme.
        - "Darlin' Corey" - Bob Johnson and Norm Blake and the Lonesome Travelers
          9 p.m. time slot. Song fragment.
        - Pet Milk ad
    - Side 2
      - Grand Ole Opry show
        - "Take This Hammer" - Osborne Brothers
        - "Worried Man Blues" - Osborne Brothers
        - "Weary Blues" - Brother Oswald
        - "Cripple Creek" - Stringbean [David Akeman]
        - "The Chain Gang" - Bill Napier and Charlie Moore
        - "Las Cassas, Tennessee" - Jim and Jesse
        - "Lost Indian" - Crook Brothers
      - Tut Taylor & The Folkswingers With 12-Sting Guitar – 12 String Dobro!, 1964
        Selections from World Pacific 1816. Includes Glen Campbell (12-string guitar); John Piazza (6-string guitar), Leroy Vinnegar (bass).
        - "Foggy Mountain Rock"
        - "Fireball Mail"
        - "Eastwood Shuffle"
        - "Big Ball in Boston"
        - "Brown's Ferry Blues"
        - "Bury Me Beneath the Willow"
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, AFC 2002/009: SR001; RXH 8870; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Side 1: 01:03:55, Side 2: 01:03:24): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, and others, including J. Fender, at Bean Blossom live, October 22, 1961
        Recorded at the afternoon show, Bean Blossom, Indiana, with Bobby Smith (guitar), Vassar Clements (fiddle), Neil Rosenberg (banjo), Birch Monroe (bass).
        - "Bill Cheatham"
        - "Footprints in the Snow"
        - "Lonesome Wind Blues"
        - "Georgia Rose"
        - "Rawhide"
        - "Uncle Pen"
        - "Muleskinner Blues"
        - "I'm On My Way to the Old Home" - Jim Maynard (guitar and vocal)
        - "Wait a Little Longer Please Jesus" - Birch Monroe (bass and vocal)
        - "Precious Memories"
        - "Crying Holy"
        - "Panhandle Country"
        - "Down Yonder"
          The tape was changed at this point in the recording.
        - "Bile Them Cabbage Down"
        - "Raggedy Ann"
        - "Mother's Not Dead"
        - "When the Roses Bloom Again" - Pat Burton (guitar and vocal)
        - "Act Like a Married Man" - Carol Logston
        - "A Beautiful Life"
        - "Y'all Come"
      - Bill Monroe, September 24, 1961
        Recorded at the evening show, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Same personnel except Shorty Shehan plays the string bass.
        - "Little Maggie"
        - "Are You Missing Me?"
        - "It's Been a Blue, Blue Day"
        - "I Wish That I Could Fall in Love Today"
        - "Katy Hill"
        - "White Lightnin'"
          The song ends abruptly
    - Side 2
      - Bill Monroe, September 24, 1961
        - "White Lightnin'"
          Complete version.
        - "On and On"
        - "Uncle Pen"
        - "Y'all Come"
      - Bill Monroe, October 22, 1961
        Recorded on Sunday afternoon at Bean Blossom, Indiana, with Bobby Smith (guitar), Vassar Clements (fiddle), Neil Rosenberg (banjo), Jimmy Maynard (guitar).
        - "Are You Missing Me"
        - "Family Bible"
        - "Cripple Creek"
        - "Orange Blossom Special"
        - "Life to Go"
        - "I'm Going Down and Have Myself a Ball"
          Jim Maynard
        - "Smoking Cigarettes and Drinking Coffee Blues"
      - Jocko Keithly (guitar), Jesse Fender (mandolin), Hubert Ratliff (guitar), October 22, 1961
        Recorded on Sunday afternoon at Bean Blossom, Indiana.
        - "I'm a Sad Weary Cowboy" - Jocko Keithly
        - "What Am I Living For" - Hubert Ratliff
        - "Don't You Wanna Go Back to Terre Haute" - mandolin tune by Jesse Fender
        - "When I Lay My Burden Down"
        - unidentified mandolin tune
      - Stanley Miller (guitar and vocal), Bob Evans (electric guitar), October 22, 1961
        - "Deep Elum Blues"
        - unidentified song
      - Jim Phillips Bessire, bass; Juanita Shehan, guitar; Neil Rosenberg, banjo; Shorty Shehan, fiddle; Ann Rosenberg, autoharp, August 20, 1961
        Recorded on Sunday afternoon at the Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana.
        - "Foggy Mountain Top"
        - "Out Behind the Barn"
        - "Bury Me Beneath the Willow"
        - "Cumberland Gap"
        - "All the Good Times"
        - "No One to Sing for Me"
          Continued on SR002.
  - Banjo contest, August 20, 1961, AFC 2002/009: SR002; RXH 8871; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 01:04:03, Side 2: 00:15:20): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Banjo contest
        Judges: 1) Art Rosenbaum 2) Neil Rosenberg and Pat Burton 3) Jack Perry
        - "Cumberland Gap"
        - "Home Sweet Home" - Jack Perry (banjo), Bryant Wilson (guitar)
        - "Cripple Creek"
        - "Bury Me Beneath the Willow" - Neil Rosenberg and Pat Burton (double banjo), Ann Burton Williams (guitar)
        - "Bile Them Cabbage Down"
        - "Old Scolding Wife" - Art Rosenbaum (banjo), Shorty Shehan (guitar), Juanita Shehan (x)
      - Jack Perry (banjo), Bryant Wilson (guitar), Shorty Shehan (fiddle)
        - "Little Darlin' Pal of Mine"
        - "Stand Still"
        - "Chokin' the Strings"
      - Pat Burton and Neil Rosenberg, banjos; Shorty Shehan (unidentified instrument); Ann Williams, guitar
        - "Some Day We'll Meet Again, Sweetheart"
        - "Once More"
        - "Wedding Bells"
        - "Reuben"
        - "Uncle Pen"
        - "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms"
      - Art Rosenbaum, banjo; Shorty Shehan, fiddle; Juanita Shehan, guitar
        - "Down Old Plank Road"
        - "Shady Grove"
    - Side 2
      - Art Rosenbaum, banjo; Shorty Shehan, fiddle; Juanita Shehan, guitar
        - "Shady Grove"
          Complete version
        - "Pretty Polly"
      - Neil Rosenberg, banjo; Shorty and Juanita
        - "In the Garden"
        - "Arkansas Traveler"
        - "Little Maggie"
        - "The Old Rugged Cross"
          Fades out
  - Stanley Brothers at Wilder Lounge, Oberlin College, March 11, 1962, AFC 2002/009: SR003; the original recording was made by Nancy Decker.; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, Side 1: 00:32:57, Side 2: 00:33:13): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Personnel: Ralph Stanley, bass and tenor; Carter Stanley, guitar and lead; George Shuffler, lead guitar and bass/baritone; Chick Stripling, bass fiddle, comedy
    - Side 1
      - "Cripple Creek"
      - "The Legend of the Brown Mountain Lights"
        George Shuffler, vocal
      - "Clinch Mountain Backstep"
      - "Sunny Side of the Mountain"
      - "Riding That Midnight Train"
      - "Johnson's Old Grey Mare"
      - "Can You Forgive?"
      - "Wildwood Flower"
      - "John Henry, The Steel Drivin' Man"
    - Side 2
      - "John Henry"
      - "Little Willie"
        Ralph Stanley, vocal
      - "Katie Cline"
      - "How Mountain Girls Can Love"
      - "Butter Paddle Buck and Wing" ("Chicken Reel")
        Tap dance by Chick Stripling
      - "Cumberland Gap"/"Cripple Creek"
      - Theme - "Long Journey Home"
  - The Country Gentlemen at Oberlin College, May 13, 1961, AFC 2002/009: SR004; RXI 0135; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:48, Side 2: 00:31:46): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    According to Neil Rosenberg, this was probably recorded by Nancy Decker, who recorded Oberlin College Folksong Club events. Banter between songs throughout. Continued on SR005 and SR136
    - Side 1
      The source tape identifies this recording as Side 2; the digital copy has been inadvertently identified as Side 1.
      - Theme: "Foggy Mountain Breakdown"
      - intro joke
      - "I Ain't Gonna Work Tomorrow"
      - "The Story of Charlie Lawson"
      - "John Hardy"
      - bow joke
      - drunk joke
      - "Glass of Wine"
      - watches joke